today i'm going to show you guys how to
make your audio sound as good as
possible
inside of final cut pro 10. so if you're
a beginner and you don't even know much
about
audio editing this is the perfect video
for you i'm going to walk you step by
step
everything that i do to my videos when
editing them to make the audio sound as
good as possible
you gotta just press record now before
we get into this tutorial it's
definitely recommended to wear
headphones when you are audio editing
typically your headphones are gonna be
so much better to listen to audio
than something like a built-in computer
speaker or a monitor speaker most people
don't have expensive
speakers but they do have some
headphones laying around so plug those
in and that's going to be better off
for you to start editing your audio so
here in final cut pro 10 you can see
that i do have
some clips down here and we are going to
be editing the audio of these video
clips
to make it sound as good as possible i'm
going to walk you through
everything that i do step by step so you
guys can see exactly my process
not saying that my process is the best
process but if you are a beginner i
promise you you are going to learn a few
things here that are going to make your
audio sound a lot better so stay to the
end of this video so you do not miss out
but the first thing that i like to do is
actually the eq now this is something
that i didn't do for a long time because
i was just kind of overwhelmed with it
and to be honest i'm not a professional
when it comes to doing this so i'm going
to show you what i do and i'm going to
try and teach it in a basic way that a
beginner could follow and understand
and practice some of this stuff in your
own video so let's get right into it
first thing we want to do is to select a
clip that we want to edit
so i'm going to go ahead and select this
first clip and if we hit play we can
hear that the audio
right now then you are hearing me sounds
fine but it's a little bit low
we are going to fix that next but i am
going to adjust the eq
first and then you'll see why i do that
first later but what we do
is we go up here and we are going to see
this little sound mixer box
this sound mixer box if we click this
it's going to open up
see equalization it's going to open up
this window right here
this is called the graphic equalizer
right now it's set to flat and you can
see that each point is set to zero
decibels now if i raise
this point which is 32 hertz this is
going to be at 12 decibels and that's
going to raise
that lower basey frequency up higher so
that it's louder
or i could reduce that to negative 20 db
and that is going to make it very very
quiet so
each of these decibels are related to a
different hurts a different
frequency dragging them up are gonna
emphasize that make them louder
dragging them down are gonna get rid of
that now the reason
i use this is to actually make my audio
sound
better so i adjust these up and down and
it can actually make
your microphone sound a lot cleaner a
lot smoother
and sometimes when recording on dslrs or
mirrorless cameras
it just doesn't sound full it doesn't
sound super good
and actually just messing with this a
little bit can make your voice
sound a lot cleaner and honestly can
really make a cheap microphone sound
expensive if you get this right like
they can sound really really good
if you mess with these settings
correctly now what i like to do is
actually set this first
clip on a loop and it's really simple to
do this you need to make sure that your
loop
playback is on all you got to do is hit
command l and that is going to turn it
on
or if it's already on that would turn it
off but command l to turn it back on
and then instead of hitting the space
bar for play like we always do
we're going to hit this forward slash
button hitting this button is going to
play it and then put it on a loop so
that it goes over and over again
and as it's playing you're going to see
me do a few things here you're going to
see me moving this up and down seeing
what sounds better now typically voices
don't
fall in this range or in this range it's
usually
in that middle range and so these i
might be able to move around a little
bit but i won't really notice
much until i get into this range of the
eq
another thing i'm looking for here is
the background ac
unit there is a noise removal plug-in
that i'm going to show you guys how to
use
but actually messing with this i might
be able to find that maybe the ac
is on a specific channel frequency and
if i pull it down
it's going to get rid of that so i'm
looking to get rid of some of those
unwanted noises by lowering the
frequency and then i'm looking to kind
of mess with the rest of them
to get my voice sounding as clear and
full as possible
so we're gonna go ahead and loop this
and then i am going to mess with the eq
if you're listening to this audio right
now then you are hearing me edit this
audio to make it sound better
if you're listening to this audio right
now then you are hearing me edit this
audio to make it sound better
so right here you can see as i pulled
this up it's actually
increasing the ac unit in the background
so i definitely don't want to do that
and by the way you never want to boost
any of these up to 20 decibels
i usually boost them if i'm going to
boost them around the six decibel mark
um but you do not want to go that high
but the reason i'm doing that now
is so i can hear it better and i go okay
this is where the ac unit is falling in
and so these are the kind of things that
i'm listening for while editing
listening to this audio right now then
you are hearing me edit this audio to
make it sound better
all right now in this channel i'm also
really getting
that ac unit as well i'm gonna hit play
so you guys can hear that
now then you are hearing me edit this
audio to make it sound better
now instead of just reducing this all
the way to get rid of that noise
this ac unit sound is actually tied to
some of the same frequencies as my voice
so it's going to sound a bit funny
if i just pull this all the way down if
you're listening to this audio right now
it sounds pretty dead my voice kind of
sounds like it's coming through a
telephone or a walkie-talkie
so this is where you really have to kind
of play back and forth go through it a
few times and see what's going to sound
best because you want to take away some
of those noises you don't want
but you also want your voice sounding
really nice
audio to make it sound better if you're
listening to this audio right now then
you are hearing me edit this
so in this channel i feel like as i pull
it up i'm starting to get that
walkie-talkie telephone effect again and
it's making my voice just sound a lot
less
full and so bringing that up i
definitely don't want to do i'm going to
leave it at zero
i could even bring it down a little bit
if i don't want that but for now i'm
going to leave it at zero and move on to
the next one
if you're listening to this audio right
now then you are hearing me edit this
audio to make it sound better
if you're listening to this audio right
now then you are hearing me edit this
audio to make it sound better
if you're listening to this audio right
now then you are hearing me edit this
audio to make it sound better
if you're listening to this audio right
now then you are hearing me edit this
audio to make it
now once i've gone through i made some
simple adjustments i'll put it on loop
and i'll kind of click it on and off to
see how it
sounds if it's if it's starting to sound
worse then i'm doing something wrong if
it's starting to sound better i'm on the
right track
what i'll do is i'll go back through
these again and i'll start to just tweak
them
little by little until i get something
that i'm happy with you are hearing me
edit this audio to make it sound better
if you're listening to this audio right
now then you are hearing
so i definitely feel with it on i am
getting less of that ac
unit sound in the background and i feel
like my voice is a little bit fuller
there's a few things i can tweak here so
i'm going to play it through a couple
more times
and just make some small tweaks to the
eq
if you're listening to this audio right
now then you are hearing me edit this
audio
now it's just a subtle difference but i
do definitely think this sounds a whole
lot better and so i'm pretty happy with
how this is sounding
once i'm done all you got to do is hit
that x and this is going to save
everything so i'm going to hit x and now
what i can do is i can see over here
and turn off and on just from this tab
right here if i do want to go back in
and make some changes
i can click on that sound board again
and this is going to pull up
the same window now one thing that i
like to add here and there i don't use
it all the time but i do really like
using it and it's helped me a lot
and that's the compressor now to find it
if you go to the effects tab by clicking
on this you are going to see that it's
set to video
but if you scroll down you are going to
see audio and it says all we can click
on that
and from here we can search for
compressor you can drag that onto your
clip now watch what happens to the
waveform when i let go
it's going to boost stuff up now the
compressor is really good
for boosting up low ends where stuff is
quiet
and it's also good for not clipping
those high ends it tries to keep
everything
together more level so here's a great
example when i was shooting my how to
vlog
video with my wife we had one shotgun
microphone right in between us
but i just talked a little bit louder
than her so her audio
was a lot quieter and so when i threw
the compressor on it brought her voice
up so that we were at about the same
audio level
and that i wasn't much louder than her
but we both had that same
loudness now there's a whole lot that
you can do with compressor if you open
up the parameters you can mess with all
these and see what's going to sound best
for you
typically what i do sometimes is just
leave it how it
is now this is the beginner's tutorial
so i am not going to touch
anything but you can see here even the
audio form looks a lot
like a lot more level it doesn't look
like the low parts are as low so if i
listen to this back things are going to
sound a lot louder that work quieter and
so you can hear what that sounds like
if you're listening to this audio right
now then you are hearing me edit this
audio to make it sound better
now again i don't always love using the
compressor because what i found is
sometimes when you
are quiet and it boosts stuff up it can
boost up that background noise like the
ac
or other things like that so definitely
something to experiment with but it can
be a lifesaver like it was for me
on that video with my wife and ended up
sounding really really good for this
clip i'm actually going to remove that
and my next step that i would do if i
was editing this
is to set my audio levels i like to do
the compressor first because that kind
of messes with that but setting the
audio
levels is really simple all you need to
do is drag this
up and down so you can see if i drag it
up to 12 db
that's going to make it as loud as
possible or if i drag it down
that is going to make it quieter now
when setting your audio levels you want
to make sure that nothing is clipping
above this zero db audio levels right
here so if i play it through
i'm gonna see where this is falling i
want it to fall right around negative
six
uh even if it goes up above that that's
fine as long as it doesn't pass over
zero if you're listening to this audio
right now then you are hearing me edit
this audio to make it sound better
so it sounds pretty good i honestly
could increase that to
uh you know seven or eight but if you
notice something right here right right
when i
tried to pull that up it just jumped up
to 12. well what you can do to do
precise adjustments is hold down the
command button and then when you do this
i can go from six to seven to eight
pretty easily because it slows
everything down so i'm going to go ahead
and move that to 7
and that is a nice little hack that you
can do one other thing you can do is go
up here and you can actually just change
your db by typing this in if i want to
go to 7.5
or something you can do that and you can
also
drag this as well i'm gonna leave mine
at 7 db
i'll do one last check make sure it's
not clipping in this beginning part
where it's nice and loud and it looks
perfect the next thing that i might add
is a noise removal this can help get rid
of that background noise and so
if i go up here and i go to my audio
analysis tab and i click
show this is going to give us some more
options and you can see right here it
says noise removal if i click that it's
automatically set to 50
and typically this is a bit too much i
find that it kind of distorts the voice
too much it just doesn't sound the best
so we're gonna hit play
and see how this sounds at 50 percent if
you're listening to this audio right now
then you are
it's actually taking away from the
quality of the voice and so i am going
to bring this down
even though it did get rid of that
background noise and it's just my voice
you don't hear the ac at all it's not
worth it because
it just doesn't sound as good if you're
listening to this audio right now then
you are hearing me edit this audio to
make it sound better now
then you are hearing me edit this audio
to make it sound so what i found is
right at 30
for this clip specifically it gets rid
of that background noise without messing
with my voice a bunch
and again i don't even use this all the
time because it can mess with your voice
so much
and i actually have a video on how to
record your audio with no background
noise so definitely check that out by
clicking the link in the description
that's going to save your life because
you do not want to be using this noise
removal
but if you get into an instance where
you might need to
this is always there to help save you if
you need it
so let's say that we like this audio and
we want to copy and paste it to all the
clips in the timeline what you can do is
you can click your clip you can hit
command c and then if you select both
your other clips
if you hit shift command v this is going
to be
paste attributes now the other clips
already have
a color wheels and a hue saturation on
them
i just want to copy over these audio
attributes so i'm going to
deselect everything on this side and
from this i can copy and paste all this
which looks great i'll hit paste
and now all my clips are going to have
the same audio
everything that i just changed on that
first clip is now on all my clips
alright so i got a few more things to
show you guys but first like this video
and then comment down below
what other final cut pro 10 tutorials do
you want to see from me
let me know in the comments down below
so i just dragged some music into my
timeline and i have a few more tips for
you guys that's going to help a lot with
your videos
and so first off one major mistake that
i see a lot of people do is they add in
their backup music
way too loud and so i like to start by
bringing mine down all the way to about
negative
32 decibels now really this is just
by ear and hearing how it sounds with
your video and obviously if like the
chorus or the drop happens in this
in the song that might need to come a
little bit lower but you just want to
listen to this and
honestly i tell people you'd rather
under do it than overdo it because i've
clicked off videos before where
the background music was just too loud
and it's annoying so again you'd rather
just bring that a little bit too low
than a little bit too high
if you're listening to this audio right
now then you are hearing me edit this
audio to make it sound better now i
can't even hear that music so i'm gonna
actually bring that up
what i've noticed is that usually the
chorus or the loudest part of the song
that is going to be around negative 32
sometimes these beginning parts
in in the video can be anywhere at
negative 16 negative 12
really just depends on the song but
that's just something to listen for
as you're editing the music if you're
listening to this audio right now then
you are hearing me edit this audio to
make it sound better
like that sounds pretty good right at
negative 20 db it's just in the
background it's not overpowering
but we can see here as it starts to get
louder i'll show you guys how to
actually make that quieter so let's say
actually right at this part
right here we want to boost this part of
the song maybe there's going to be some
b-roll or
something cool is happening and there's
no one talking so we just want to
increase the audio of the music so that
it kind of takes over the video now how
you do this is you can hit
r and this is going to bring up your
range selector
and once you select how much you want of
this song
to increase you can then drag it back up
like this
most people want to bring it to zero
because that's how
it just imports as zero decibels but
that actually is going to be
too loud because when i'm talking you
know how we recorded stuff and
it ends up being around negative six
decibels well that's what i found is
that you don't want
your music really going over negative
six decibels sometimes because
it can just sound really really loud
compared to your voice when you're
talking
you can see that i also have some
keyframes here and you can totally move
these around if you want it to fade in
slower
or if you want it to fade in really
quickly you can move these closer
together and you still can change the
loudness right here by dragging it up
and down
better and a lot cleaner
okay well i think that sounds pretty
good again this stuff is all by ear so
what i recommend
is watching some videos that you like on
youtube
listening to it and hearing how their
background music comes in is it really
loud
is it really quiet and try to match that
in your editing
so let's say this is the end of the
video if you want to fade out the music
right here we are going to can't see it
right now with the playhead over it but
right here we're going to see
this little icon and if you drag this
over this allows you to
fade out the music so if i drag it over
even more
it's going to fade out even slower this
would be a very quick fade out and so
this is what that sounds like
if you want to fade out the music
now same at the beginning i usually like
to fade in the beginning of my music
just a little bit and you can do that at
the beginning as well
just by doing that you can do the same
thing with a video clip so if i want to
fade in the audio
of this video clip you can drag this in
as well you can do that on any clip
audio
video you can fade it in or fade it out
now if you want to separate your audio
if you click on a video you can right
click
and then you can detach the audio and
this is going to
allow you to extend this over and maybe
fade it in
and then i can do the same thing with
this one as well and this is going to
allow your clips to be smoother as they
transition into each other especially if
you're talking quick
and your cuts are fast this is going to
help from any sort of weird pops that
might happen
if you're like a frame off and it's
cutting off the very beginning of your
word
if you detach your audio you can
actually extend that
so that your word or whatever you're
saying is finishing
and you can also use this in many ways
so knowing how to detach the audio is a
very useful thing
just right click detach audio now i just
found out about this trick this last
year and it's been
really really cool because i didn't even
know you could do this but i've loved
using that and that is soloing a track
so let's say you added in your music
maybe you have your sound effects you
have everything
in but you want to edit your audio you
forgot to edit your audio and that's
fine you don't have to edit your audio
first when editing a video but let's say
you have
all the sound effects all this music and
now it's time for you to do the eq
adjust the levels well what you can do
instead of playing this with music over
it like this
audio right now then you are hearing me
you can either select
your audio clip and hit v and that's
going to disable this clip so if i play
this again
right now then you are hearing me now
all you can hear is my voice i can click
on the clip i can edit the eq i can do
whatever i want to this clip but let's
say there's a bunch of sound effects and
maybe a whole bunch of other stuff
happening another way you can do this
let's go ahead and hit v on that again
another way you can do this is click on
the clip that you want to solo out
and then you can hit these headphones
and that is going to make
everything else in this timeline grayed
out because
it's all muted and now all that you can
hear is the clip you have selected and
you can also select
all the clips you want let's say you
want all the talking head clips just to
be selected you can select
all of those you can then hit the
headphone icon and that's going to work
as well
the shortcut for this is option s so
let's say i want to select all my
talking head because i want to go ahead
and edit that audio i can hit
option s and that's going to disable
everything else
so when i'm editing this audio all i
hear
is my voice click on the screen to watch
another final cut pro 10 tutorial
and i'll see you guys in the next video
[Applause]
[Music]